# Rishi Soni

Indore, India (452009) <u>rishisoni.in</u> <u>rishisoni.in</u> <u>rishisoni.in</u> <u>rishisoni.in</u> <u>rishisoni.in</u>

## **Professional Summary:**

Experienced Software Engineer - Frontend with a background in LeetCode problem-solving and Front-end development. Began as an intern at Web Function and currently working at Apisero Inc. skilled in using front-end technologies such as JavaScript and React.

### **Experience:**

> Organization : Apisero Inc.

➤ Designation : Software Engineer – Aug 2021 to Present – 1.8 Years

Organization : Putatoe Technologies Pvt. Ltd.

➤ Designation : Frontend Developer Intern – Aug 2020 to Nov 2020 – **3 Months** 

#### **Technical Skills:**

Languages: Python3, JavaScript, Core Java, SQL (MySQL), HTML5, CSS3.

- > Softwares & Tools: Git-Github, Postman, VS Code, Automation Anywhere.
- ➤ Good Understanding of Problem-Solving, Data Structures, DBMS, Object-Oriented Programming Concepts, SDLC, and Software Design Patterns.
- Experience with various Front-end JavaScript libraries such as **React.js** (Hooks), Redux, Material-Ui, NPM Libraries and CSS frameworks.
- > Basic understanding of frontend tools such as Webpack and Babel.
- ➤ Good working experience with DOM & Web services integration (RESTful APIs, JSON, Ajax, Axios).

# **Education Qualification:**

- > Completed Bachelor of Technology from Shivajirao Kadam Institute of Technology & Management
  - Indore with specialization in Computer Science (2018-2022).
- ➤ High School and Higher Secondary School Certificate (10+2) from MP State Board.

### **Project Undertaken:**

- In Apisero, worked on multiple projects such as Bidding based Job Portal, L&D Dasboard and Resource Demand Dashboard.
- > JAMstack Ecommerce Everything which an eCommerce App possesses & built with ReactJS.
- > Netflix Clone Complete replica of Netflix with trailer, screenshot, search, etc. functionalities.
- ➤ <u>News Website</u> Integrated web-services to provide real-time data with pagination.
- > Cover Letter Generation & Instagram Automation with RPA (Robotic Process Automation).

### **Achievements:**

- Solved 300+ problems on LeetCode & regular coder on GeeksForGeeks as well.
- > Five Star Rated in Python, SQL, and Java on HackerRank.

#### **Personal Details:**

Date of Birth : 06/07/2001 Languages known : Hindi, English